It's autumn, Ioryogi! It smells like autumn!
Huh? Smells like autumn?
What do you mean?
A little like smoke, and a little like sunshine.
It's a brisk, refreshing feeling.
It makes me feel nostalgic.
You don't remember anything, but you still know what autumn smells like?
Ioryogi!
What?
What's that?
Wow!
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... Angel and Guardian.
I've never seen such a wonderful gingko tree.
It really is autumn.
What's wrong? You don't seem happy.
Hey, Kobato.
Look at this. You know what it is, right?
Um... When it's fall, the leaves all get dressed up pretty and dance in the wind!
Who told you to let your imagination get that overactive?
Kobato! What do you want!?
Umm...
Don't tell me you forgot!?
To go where I want to!
And what do you need to do to get there?
Umm...
Collect candy!
And what do you need to do to collect candy?
Heal people's scarred hearts!
How long do you have?
Until the four seasons pass!
How many do you have left?
Two!
And how much do you have?
Umm...
This much.
Kobato.
Yes?
You know where that place is, don't you.
Yes.
Got it.
Hey, look out! You'll lose your hat!
Okay...
C'mon.
Good morning!
Whatever! I hate you, Toshihiko!
What's wrong? You shouldn't tell people you hate them!
Yuzuru and Toshihiko are arguing over blocks.
My train needs a triangle, but Toshihiko took them both!
I needed to put them together to make a square!
Aren't there any squares left?
Why don't we all make something big togther? Maybe a castle?
Never mind!
If you don't take care of those, I'm going to take them away.
Whatever, they suck.
That's right! They're dirty used junk you should just throw away!
Don't, Fujimoto!
Don't get mad, Mister Kiyokazu!
Hey.
Hey, Kobato!
Huh?
Ioryogi? I hear you, but I can't see you.
Ioryogi!
You moron!
Quit wasting your time!
You think you're gonna get any candy doing that!?
You're right, but...
Kobato.
What happened with Fujimoto before he left for work?
He usually at least says goodbye...
I wonder what's wrong.
Um...
What?
I see.
So that's what happened.
He didn't look angry, just sad.
I'm sorry I didn't realize.
It's not your fault.
He's just like that.
I wish we could get new toys for the kids to cool them down.
Toys...
I know! I know just the place!
Just the place?
Hey, where are we going?
Somewhere fun!
What a big tree!
Today we're all going to collect leaves!
When we're done, we'll bring them back and make pictures with them!
Pictures?
They come in all different shapes and colours.
I wonder what kind of pictures you'll make?
I'll get some!
Yeah, us too!
Look, Miss Sayaka! A pretty leaf!
Oh my.
You can have it!
You too, Kobato!
Are you sure?
Sorry.
Um... About the blocks...
Will you promise me you'll take good care of them?
I will!
Then...
What do you do after you fight?
Sorry.
You need to apologise to Fujimoto later.
Okay!
We'll give Mister Kiyokazu plenty of leaves too!
Good, they made up.
They don't normally argue that often.
It must be because I'm worried.
Don't be! A smile fits you better!
Thanks.
If I keep frowning, it'll scare happy things away, won't it.
Yeah, smile, smile!
Wow, it's amazing.
It looks like it's aflame.
Yeah.
It's so beautiful and tranquil.
Get back! It's dangerous!
Um... What are you doing?
We're chopping that tree down tomorrow. Today, we're putting a fence up around it.
That ginkgo tree?
Why?
The locals have been complaining about it.
They want it out of the way.
No way! It's so splendid and beautiful!
And because it's so splendid, the leaves go all over.
Besides, there's a new urban renewal program.
Now if you'll excuse us-
Ioryogi?
Huh?
What's urban renewal?
It's when they tear down old towns or buildings and make new ones.
That's urban renewal?
Yeah.
Are old things that unwanted?
It's not like that.
Most people just like new things.
Hey, it's not time to go back to the nursery yet.
I'll go ask them!
Huh?
I'll ask them not to cut it down!
What?
Hey, hold on!
If I ask, they'll-!
Kohaku?
Good morning, Kobato and Ioryogi.
Kohaku, you're worried about the ginkgo tree too?
This urban renewal is terrible for old things!
Really?
But I'll ask them, so it'll be fine!
I see.
Just what will be fine?
Huh, they didn't have this fence up yesterday.
They're doing urban renewal!
Oh my. Well, they've been discussing it for a while.
It's an impressive tree, but thiss will make it easier for the people who live here.
That's too bad.
But renewal is good.
Wow, what a big tree.
It's kind of spooky.
I guess.
Oh no, look at the time!
What's wrong, Kobato?
It's nothing.
She must be unhappy everyone else doesn't mind.
It's not that.
Then what is it?
Isn't the tree lonely?
Lonely?
It's been here watching this town grow for decades or even centuries.
But no one worries about it.
Don't worry, Kobato.
It says it's not lonely.
You can understand what it's thinking?
Yeah, somehow.
Are you just playing dumb? You know Kohaku's an angel.
Um... Is it thinking anything else?
It's happy the little ones had so much fun under it yesterday.
Is there anything else I can do?
It says thanks. And...
Goodbye...
Don't worry! I'll ask them not to cut you down!
It doesn't seem like it wants that.
I'll move it!
Huh? Hey!
Kobato...
Hey, don't overdo it.
But... But!
But if I don't they're gonna-!
I knew a wisteria that had lived this long.
It said the same thing.
The same thing?
That it was happiest watching over the people that it loved.
Can you hear its song?
Yes... It's a little sad, but so kind.
On the shore in the autumn
In winter, sleeping in the treetops
The endless kindness of this world
As night falls, let us offer our prayers
And silently welcome tomorrow's sun
A faraway voice leads me on
Like it's smiling, like it's singing
The echoing sound of the wind
Joy and sadness
I embrace them both and keep going
My hand and yours
Join together strongly
Hey!
The tree-
That was dangerous!
What were you doing just standing there!?
Sorry...
So that's all it had left...
The core was rotted out. Sooner or later, it would've been cut.
It tried to hold on just a little bit longer.
Kohaku...
Was it happy?
Happy?
I'm sure it was.
Your singing saw it off.
Ioryogi?
Whose candy could this be?
Kohaku's?
No, I don't think so.
Fujimoto's!? Nah, no way.
Maybe it's from that ginkgo tree.
It was still alive.
Wouldn't be too weird if it's what you healed.
But I wasn't able to save it.
You sang, right?
A song?
What did Kohaku tell you?
Your song sent it off.
It was happy in the end.
I see.
There! How is it?
Fujimoto, let's make one!
That's...
These are blocks!
I'm making them out of that ginkgo.
The ginkgo?
That's wonderful, Fujimoto!
I guess.
Everyone! Fujimoto's making new blocks!
Toshihiko! Yuzuru! Don't you have something to say to Fujimoto before you play with them?
Sorry, Mister Kiyokazu!
Uh, thanks.
Good, everyone's made up!
Hey, Mister Kiyokazu, make a leaf picture with us!
I'm not really-
We'll stick on ginkgo leaves, and make a ginkgo Fujimoto alien!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Searching at Sunset.
Next episode